Let's learn about Phil Binary Tree.
A full binary tree is a special type of binary tree in which every parent node or internal node has
either two or no children.
It is also known as a proper binary tree.
This is an example of by a full binary tree.
The algorithm theorem behind making it for binary tree is considering that the number of leaves is that
equal to the number of internal nodes plus one.
The total number of nodes is equal to two times the number of internal nodes plus one.
The number of internal nodes is equal to N minus one over two and would be the number of total number
of notes.
But the number of lives is equal to NUM total number of nodes plus one over two.
And the total number number of nodes is two times number of lives minus one.
And the number of internal nodes is equal to L minus one, which is the number of lives minus one.
And the number of lives is at most is due to power a number of levels minus one.
We are not going.
I just mentioned this theory, but all what we need and what we are interested in is the code.
So how we write the full binary tree in C.
Starting by include SD, the eye ball as the ball SD diode and SD I, that's to the left, we create
A..
And item.
And we create a no reference left and right.
So this would be the basic structure of the end of any three.
And we have seen it before, the creation of a new note struck note, we create a new note method.
And it took into the meters, the car key and I have created here a tree or that accepts the car, not
integers.
You can make it integers, the strings, any other object.
But the the target and the goal from making these data structures is the algorithm and how we think,
how we create not the syntax.
OK.
We start by making and allocating the memory by note, and we put a stop to that item data and the note
data is equal to K.
Then note right is equal to the note left equal to not initialize them equal to null.
And with then we have seen this in the previous video in that three traversal methods and three traversal
exercises.
OK.
Now, let's make a method called bull is full binary tree structure node three.
And it took it to the perimeter of the road note, and we start checking the three empty a fruit equal
equal to now than it is an empty tree.
Check the presence of the children a fruit left it will not and route right.
It will then then return it to.
So if it is full binary tree, it should have the left and the right equal to none.
So.
It has either two or no children.
So this is the presence of the children checking, and we are going to check that the route left, the
left section and the road section of any node is equal to now.
Then it is returning to if the route left and the route right, they are through and return.
This is full binary tree.
Start making the recursive method here to their left and to the right.
So if we have many children, we start checking it to their left.
It is a full binary tree to the left and it is full binary to the right by by specifying and the checking.
And if the left side has either two or no children and the right section and the right sub tree is equal
to and have either two or no children.
These both conditions should be true in order to return as binary tree function to true.
Otherwise, it will return false if we need to test this method.
This program, we start by going to end main and we create the root and we initialize the root by creating
node equal to one.
So we have created the new node equal to one, and we start creating this tree that it is in the picture
here.
OK?
We specify them creating one two, three, four, five, six and seven.
If binary tree is a tree binary or is full binary tree, we passed the rule, that tree is a full binary
tree.
If it is true, otherwise it will print.
The tree is not full binary tree.
And in this example, it will return for us.
It is through and the tree is full binary tree.
This is very important question that you may ask in in your interview or in your university to check
it.
Three or a given tree is full binary tree, and I told you that the tree and the key behind the checking
it is by by checking the root left and the right equal equal to null.
And if they are having data, then the root left and the right is.
Full binary tree to the left and full binary tree to the right, so we are going to check up this sub
tree is fully binary tree and we check the right section if it is fully binary tree.
If it is true here and true to their left, then it would be a full binary.